therapynotes.com 2017-03-17

# TherapyNotes Privacy Policy

At TherapyNotes, we are committed to protecting your privacy and the privacy of your personal information. This Privacy Policy explains the use of information collected via our Website and in connection with our provision of services to you (the "Service"). Your use of the Service indicates to us that you have read and accept our privacy practices, as outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

**This privacy policy agreement does not pertain to protected health information entered by registered users. Section 8 of our Terms of Service agreement, found athttps://www.therapynotes.com/legal/usertermsofservice/, defines the privacy of patient information for registered members of our practice management services. **

As further described below, we collect and maintain a range of data in order to provide our services to you and maintain a safe and secure Service. Access to your personal information is limited to (a) TherapyNotes employees, and (b) service providers under contract who help with our business operations (such as to provide or help TherapyNotes provide products or services to you, provide payment, billing or similar services, or perform anti-fraud functions). As used in this Privacy Policy, the term "personal information" means any real world information that readily may be used to identify an individual, including but not limited to a first and last name, home or other physical address, an email address, phone number or other contact information. 

## Categories and Methods of Information Collection

We collect a range of personal information and usage statistics to maintain a high-quality user experience and deliver superior customer service. We request some information directly from you during registration. We gather other pieces of data indirectly from Website traffic, your computer hardware and Internet connection, or your activities within the Service, communications and usage. 

  * If you use our Website, we automatically record information related to your IP address, TherapyNotes cookie information, and aggregate information on what content you access or visit. 
  * If you provide us personal information in order to subscribe to our mailing list, we collect information to aid delivery and preferences such as email address and message performance statistics. 
  * If you register on our Website, we will track broad site usage information as well as aggregate usage of any Website community features such as downloads and forums. 
  * We track usage of customer service resources in order to ensure high quality interactions. 
  * We may collect and retain any other information relating to your account data or other activities within the Service. 
  * If you conduct transactions in connection with the Service, we may collect and retain some or all of the information related to these transactions. 
  * If you notify us of an intellectual property claim, the information in your claim notice may be shared with others. 
  * If you cease being a customer of ours, we will keep a copy of your registration file in our database for use in the event you wish to rejoin the Service, and for anti-fraud and other purposes. 

## TherapyNotes' Protection and Disclosure of Your Information

Except under certain limited circumstances set forth here and in our Terms of Service, TherapyNotes does not disclose to third parties the personal information or other account-related information you provide us, such as IP address, without your permission. You understand, however, that TherapyNotes may disclose your personal or other account-related information under the following circumstances: 

  * If we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary under applicable law, or to comply with legal process served on TherapyNotes; 
  * In order to protect and defend the rights or interests of TherapyNotes or Users of the Service; 
  * In order to report to law enforcement authorities, or assist in their investigation of, suspected illegal or wrongful activity, or to report any instance in which we believe a person may be in danger; 
  * To service providers with whom we have contracted to assist us with Service features or operations (such as anti-fraud functions, billing, collections, registration, customer support, email delivery, or age verification), to fulfill your service requests, offer new content or help us improve our Service. Our contracts with these third parties prohibit them from using any of your personal information for purposes unrelated to the product or service they are providing; 
  * To other third parties (a) to provide you with services you have requested, (b) to offer you information about our Service (e.g., events or features), or (c) to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information (or about whom you are otherwise explicitly notified and consent to when using a specific service). For instance, we may provide certain information to our payment processor, to credit card associations, banks or issuers (if you are using a credit card); and 
  * To other business entities, should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity. Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice. 

## Use of Cookies

A cookie is a small string of data which often includes an anonymous unique identifier sent to your browser from a website's computers, and stored on your computer's hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. 

You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.) However, if you reject all cookies, you may not be able to use certain of our (or other companies') web pages. 

TherapyNotes and third parties acting on our behalf use cookies for a number of purposes relating to the Website including to: 

  * Access your account information when you "log in" to our Website, forums, or other areas; 
  * Keep track of your Website session data; and 
  * Keep track of certain information that is then aggregated (i.e., not connected to your personal information), such as how you use our Website, what web pages you visit, and the frequency and length of those visits. 

## Third Party Advertisements

TherapyNotes participates in ad and/or affiliate networks operated by various third party companies. These companies collect and may use certain anonymous information about your visits to our Websites as a function of referring Internet traffic to our Website. We do not permit these companies to collect any personal information about you, such as your name, address, or email address; however, we do permit these companies to collect your IP address. These companies may set and use cookies, web beacons, pixels, or other technologies to collect anonymous information about your visits to our Websites, and may otherwise aggregate, analyze and anonymize that data. 

## Amendment of this Policy

We may need to update our Privacy Policy periodically to reflect changes in the types of information we collect, the means we use to collect information, or our usage of collected information. We will make reasonable efforts to alert you to these changes when they occur. Changes take effect immediately upon posting to our Website. 

* * *

TherapyNotes will respond to allegations of copyright violations in accordance with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA). The DMCA provides a process for a copyright owner to give notification to an online service provider concerning alleged copyright infringement. When a valid DMCA notification is received, the service provider responds under this process by taking down the offending content. On taking down content under the DMCA, we will take reasonable steps to contact the owner of the removed content so that a counter-notification may be filed. On receiving a valid counter-notification, we generally restore the content in question, unless we receive notice from the notification provider that a legal action has been filed seeking a court order to restrain the alleged infringer from engaging in the infringing activity. 

## Filing a Notification

A written notification must be made. This can be done either by fax or written letter (regular mail or courier). Emails will not be accepted unless a prior arrangement has been made. The notification must: 

  1. Identify in sufficient detail the copyrighted work that you believe has been infringed upon (i.e., describe the work that you own). 
  2. Identify the item that you claim is infringing on your copyright. 
  3. Provide a reasonably sufficient method of contacting you; phone number and email address would be preferred. 
  4. Include the following statement: "I have good faith belief that the use of the copyrighted materials described above and contained on the service is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or by protection of law." 
  5. Include the following statement: "I swear, under penalty of perjury, that the information in the notification is accurate and that I am the copyright owner or am authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed." 
  6. Sign the paper. 

Please note: The DMCA provides that you may be liable for damages (including costs and attorneys fees) if you falsely claim that an item is infringing your copyrights. We recommend contacting an attorney if you are unsure whether an object is protected by copyright laws. 

Send the written document to the designated Copyright Agent at TherapyNotes: 

Attn: Designated Copyright Agent  
TherapyNotes, LLC  
630 Fitzwatertown Rd  
Suite A4  
Willow Grove, PA, 19090 

Alternatively, fax the document to (215) 658-4551. On the cover sheet, please write ATTN: DMCA NOTIFICATION 

## Filing a counter-notification

  1. List the items that were removed by TherapyNotes. 
  2. Provide your name, address, telephone number, email address (if available). 
  3. State that you consent to the jurisdiction of Federal District Court for the judicial district in which you reside (or Philadelphia, Pennsylvania if your address is outside of the United States). 
  4. State that you will accept service of process from the person who provided notification to us of the alleged infringement or an agent of such person. 
  5. State the following: "I swear, under penalty of perjury, that I have a good faith belief that the material identified above was removed or disabled as a result of a mistake or misidentification of the material to be removed or disabled." 
  6. Sign the paper. 

Send the written document to the designated Copyright Agent at TherapyNotes: 

Attn: Designated Copyright Agent  
TherapyNotes, LLC  
630 Fitzwatertown Rd  
Suite A4  
Willow Grove, PA, 19090 

Alternatively, fax the document to (215) 658-4551. On the cover sheet, please write ATTN: DMCA COUNTER-NOTIFICATION
